Hello everyone, welcome to the wonderful world of JavaScript!
In this module, after giving a brief history of JavaScript and Web browsers,
we will explain how HTML, CSS and JavaScript are related to one another.
We will see JavaScript in action through numerous interactive examples.
We have made sure that all examples can be run directly in the course’s Web pages.
Hey, we’re teaching Web technologies, after all!
We will do that throughout the course, as you will be asked to change some code,
tweak this or that example, even if the code details are not fully explained at first.
Because, this is how we recommend beginners to learn JavaScript: first look at examples,
then tweak some code and see the results of the changes.
You will certainly encounter error messages, but no worries, as I will teach you how to
debug JavaScript code using your browser’s devtool console.
In this first module, you will also learn about JavaScript variables, operators and
expressions, and have a first lesson about functions, objects, arrays and strings.
These are the basic concepts of JavaScript and are shared by many other programming languages.
We’ll then develop together, and step by step, an interactive graphic tool that will
use many different features from JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
Let’s start having fun with JavaScript, now :-)